<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Keith's Blog</title><link href="http://idahogray.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://idahogray.github.com/feeds/work.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://idahogray.github.io/blog/</id><updated>2013-04-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Thoughts On Email</title><link href="http://idahogray.github.io/blog/thoughts-on-email.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Keith Gray</name></author><id>tag:idahogray.github.io/blog,2013-04-20:thoughts-on-email.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was listing to this &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://5by5.tv/inbeta/36"&gt;In Beta&lt;/a&gt; episode today while mowing the lawn. Gina and
Kevin were talking about email and getting to Inbox Zero and so on. One of their
comments was that email fails because it is a TODO list that other people can
add items to. This is not the first time I have heard this and I don't know
who originally said it, I couldn't find it in quick Google search. They
also made a comment about training other people that emailing you does not
mean an immediate response is coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This comment got me thinking, again, about how I use email at work. I currently
have about 71 emails that I feel like I need to respond to. This weighs on
me and I can never feel like I am caught up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This episode got me thinking about sending an automatic response to incoming
emails. Something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
Thank you for your email. If this email contains a task you would like
me to complete, I would appreciate it if you would call me. This would allow
us to properly discuss the task, its schedule, my availability, and
possible alternatives if those items don't line up.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with something like this is that I am an Engineering consultant.
We make money by being responsive to clients. The more responsive we can be,
the more likely we are to get repeat business and repeat business is the best
kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think a good compromise would be to have this response be sent to anyone
inside my company but not to our clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am just not sure how my peers and managers would respond to something like
this. So much of our business is done over email that this response may appear
to be in bad form. I think an argument could be made that a response like this
is more honest and will possibly generate more realistic discussions about
tasks and schedules than the current alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to hear any reader's thoughts, especially from those in similar
businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="work email"></category></entry></feed>