<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Keith's Blog</title><link href="http://idahogray.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://idahogray.github.com/feeds/wyatt-programming.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://idahogray.github.io/blog/</id><updated>2014-02-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>Wyatt's First Program</title><link href="http://idahogray.github.io/blog/wyatt-programming-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Keith Gray</name></author><id>tag:idahogray.github.io/blog,2014-02-02:wyatt-programming-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wyatt has shown interest in programming computers. I saw a tweet or google+ post
this week (sorry I couldn't find it again) where a father had written out
a program on a white board for his daughter to type in and run. I thought
this was a really great way to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have KTurtle installed on my
desktop at home and thought that would be a good way to get started. We have
played with Scratch a little bit but it was still a little old for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I opened one of the example programs and wrote it out on piece of paper.
Wyatt and I worked together, with him at the keyboard, to type it in.
He then ran it. Of course it didn't work the first time, what program does.
So we started debugging. I read every character in the program and he checked
to make sure his program matched. He still gets confused about some letters
so I helped him out a little bit. We got it to run!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we modified the program to make the turtle draw a different shape.
I asked if he was interested in doing more of this and he said he was.
I told him that I would print out a program for him to type in every day
before I go to work. He would type it out and tell me what the turtle
drew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did the first one last night. The turtle drew a triangle and then wrote
the word &amp;quot;triangle&amp;quot; underneath it. Here is the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;reset
repeat 3 {
    forward 100
    turnleft 120
}

go 130, 200
print &amp;quot;triangle&amp;quot;

go 0, 0
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like this exercise for a number of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wyatt gets to learn the letters of the alphabet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wyatt gets to learn the keys on the keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wyatt get introduced to logic, programming, and problem solving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think #3 is probably the most important. I know that problem solving
is one of the most important things in my job. People who can think
through a problem, figure out what is causing it, and fix it are
extremely valuable people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't wait to get Ava going on this as well!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="kids"></category><category term="programming"></category></entry></feed>